# 哈喽大家好 我是王刚
Hello everyone this is Wang Gang
# 本期视频我给大家分享一道家常菜
Today I’m going to share a homely dish
# 烧椒皮蛋
“Century Egg with Grilled Chili”
# 首先我们准备几个黄心皮蛋
Firstly, we prepare a few yellow heart century eggs
# 敲掉表皮的石灰之后再剥掉蛋壳备用
Knock off the lime on the surface and peel off the shell, then set aside
# 同学们皮蛋可以放入清水中剥离
You can peel it in water
# 这样可以防止（将）皮蛋剥烂
This way it prevents the egg to be broken
# 蛋壳剥完之后再清洗干净备用
Wash it thoroughly after peeling off the shell, then set aside
# 然后将皮蛋一切为四
Cut the egg into 4 pieces
# 皮蛋也可以多切几块
You can cut it into more pieces
# 这样摆盘份量显得更多
This way gives the dish a more satisfying presence
# 皮蛋切好之后下一步准备摆盘
Then we move on to plating
# 首先我们准备圆盘1个
Let’s prepare a round plate
# 然后将切好的皮蛋蛋黄朝下均匀地摆入盘中
Put all the egg pieces evenly on the plate with the yolks facing downwards
# 皮蛋摆好之后下一步开始准备辅料
Then we prepare the other ingredients
# 准备几个小米辣和二荆条穿入竹签备用
Prepare a few Xiaomila and Erjintiao, skew them onto bamboo skewers
# 同学们竹签必须事先泡
Remember that the bamboo skewers must be soaked in water before use
# 否则竹签很容易烧断
Otherwise it is easily burnt
# 下一步开始准备调汁
Next let’s prepare the seasoning sauce
# 准备大蒜几颗拍散之后剁碎备用
Crush a few cloves of garlic then chop them up
# 准备几根小葱头切碎备用
Chop up some scallions
# 碗中加入食用盐小半勺
Add half a spoon of salt into a bowl
# 再加入和食用盐等量的白糖
Add the same amount of sugar in the bowl
# 加入香醋3克
Add 3 g of Zhenjiang vinegar
# 加入生抽酱油10克
Add 10 g of light soy sauce
# 加入少许的香油
Add a small drizzle of sesame oil
# 然后搅拌均匀
Then mix them up evenly
# 拌匀之后再加入适量的香辣红油
After mixing, add some red chili oil
# 下一步开始准备烧辣椒
Next we grill the chilies
# 将穿好的辣椒用明火烧至干香有气泡即可
Lightly grill the skewed chilies until the skin starts to bubble
# （提示：未成年人请在成年人的陪同下制作）
(WARNING: Children must be supervised by adults at all times)
# 然后将烧好的辣椒撕成小条备用
Then tear the grilled chilies into small strips
# 同学们辣椒皮可以不用去除
Chili skin can be left on
# 这样成菜更具椒香味
This way the dish has more chili pungency
# 然后将撕好的辣椒放入盘中
Then place the chili strips on the plate
# 最后淋上调好的料汁即可上菜
Drizzle on the seasoning sauce to finish it up
# 一道非常美味的烧椒皮蛋就制作完成
A delicious dish of century eggs with grilled chilis is completed
# 下面开始技术总结
# 第一，最好选择黄心皮蛋制作，黄心皮蛋比黑心皮蛋更香
# 第二，不能吃辣的同学可以用大青椒代替二荆条
# 第三，肠胃不好的同学慎吃此菜（生辣型菜谱）
# 烧椒皮蛋的技术总结完毕
Next the technical summary
Firstly, it’s best to use yellow heart century eggs, which taste better than black heart century eggs
Secondly, for those who can’t handle spiciness, you can use green bell peppers instead
Thirdly, be careful eating this if you have a sensitive stomach
That’s it for the technical summary